Guide to the Paul A. Samuelson papers, 1933-2010 and undated RL.10082
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials, 1960-2009
  - Economics Cassette Series: Milton Friedman, 1968-1977; 2
    - Tape 179 - Chile, 1976 Economic Conditions, Prime Rate, Monetary Policy, 1975 October (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0307)
    - Tape 180 - Monetary Testimony, Australia, Corporation Taxes, 1975 November (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0308)
    - Tape 183 - T-Bill Futures Market, Evans Predictions, Monetarism, 1976 January (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0309)
    - Tape 185 - Money Targets, Natural Gas, Moynihan, Canadian Dollar, 1976 February (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0310)
    - Tape 191 - Money, Inventories, Communists in Italy, 1976 May (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0311)
    - Tape 193 - British Pound, Domestic Economy, Business Week Article, 1976 June (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0312)
    - Tape 196 - Monetary Targets, Natural Gas Prices, Monetarism in Britain, 1976 July (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0313)
    - Tape 207 - Monetary Policy, Carter Program, Energy, Business and Free Enterprise, 1977 January (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0314)
    - Tape 208 - Monetary Growth, Burn's Testimony, Reuss Letter, Rationing Water, 1977 February (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0315)
    - Unnumbered Tape - untitled, undated (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0316)
  - Miscellaneous Audiovisual Materials, 1960-2009; 3
    - Pound Devaluation - Causes and Consequences, 1967 12 December (Box 3, Audio-reel RL10082-RR-0001)
    - Samuelson's Lecture at DePaul, 1970 October 20 (Box 3, Audio-reel RL10082-RR-0002)
    - University of Cologne students' video response to Samuelson video program, 1975 June (Box 3, Video-reel RL10082-Vid1/2-0001)
    - The Economy Prize, 1970 (Box 3, Film-reel RL10082-F16-0001)
    - MR: 69-6: 5 Reel 2 of 2, Economics Seminar at Hyannisport, MA, August 3, 1960, John F. Kennedy Presidential Library and Museum, 1960 August 3 (Box 3, Audio-cd RL10082-CD-0001)
    - Paul Samuelson, 1915-2009 (Box 3, Video-disc RL10082-DVD-0001)
    - Professor Samuelson's 90th Birthday, Evening Event, 2005 (Box 3, Video-disc RL10082-DVD-0002)
    - marion, undated (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0317)
    - untitled, undated (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0318)
    - untitled, undated (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0320)
    - untitled, undated (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL10082-CS-0319)
- Awards Series, 1970-2001, 3 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, telegrams, newspaper clippings, invitations, some photographs, and other materials relating to Samuelson's winning of the Nobel Memorial Prize in Economics (1970). Also contains a file each on the Scanno Prize in Economy (1990) and the National Medal of Science (1996). The last award brought Samuelson to the White House during the Clinton presidency. Included in this series is Samuelson's correspondence, often in the form of congratulatory letters, with other Nobel laureates.
  - Nobel Prize files (Box 4)
  - National Medal of Science folder, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Nobel Prize files (Box 5)
  - Nobel Prize files (Box 6)
  - Scanno Prize in Economy, 1990 (Box 6)
- Committees and Projects Series, 1947-2009, 3 boxes
  Files document Samuelson's work on MIT committees, outside grant applications, and his service to professional organizations from just after World War II until he passed away in 2009. The earliest material relates to post-war economics (with drafts of reports and correspondence by Friedman and others). The outside grant group includes National Institutes of Health (NIH) and National Science Foundation (NSF) grant papers. The NIH grant contains his work on economic/biological analysis of population. The NSF grant contains Samuelson's work on economic theory related to stochastic processes and economic/biological mechanisms. The Irwin Friend group houses papers related to work on interest rates, the banking industry, economic growth and foreign direct investment. The National Academy of Sciences (NAS) group includes correspondence and committee work related to NAS. Included is Samuelson's referee work as part of the Editorial Board of Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. Also in this series is an NAS study on motor vehicle emissions, material on the Alfred Sloan Foundation Book Committee, and information on the TIAA-CREF's annual "Paul A. Samuelson Award." Series is arranged alphabetically by project name.
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Book Committee, 1976-1990 (Box 6)
  - Committee on Economic Stability, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - Institute for Research on Poverty, 1976-1981 (Box 6)
  - Irwin Friend Study, University of Pennsylvania, 1966-1969, 1 of 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Irwin Friend Study, University of Pennsylvania, 1966-1969, 2-4 of 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Madow Committee, 1950-1952 (Box 7)
  - MIT Policy committee, 1964 (Box 7)
  - National Academy of Sciences:
    - Correspondence, 1975-2009 (Box 7)
    - Finance Committee, 1982-2009 (Box 7)
    - Membership, 1970 (Box 7)
    - Motor Vehicle Emissions project, 1970-1973 (Box 7)
    - Nominations, 1971-1995 (Box 7)
  - Proceedings NAS Editorial Board, 1971-1976 (Box 8)
  - National Science Board, Increasing the Nation's Use of the Social Sciences, circa 1969 (Box 8)
  - National Institutes of Health Grant:
    - Biological and Economic Competition and Evolution, 1981-1985 (Box 8)
    - Economic and Biological Analysis of Population, 1977-1983 (Box 8)
    - Nonlinear Population Analysis, 1974-1977 (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - National Science Foundation Grant: Economic Theory, Stochastic Processes, and Economic-Biologic Mechanisms, 1969-1982 (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - TIAA-CREF Paul A. Samuelson Award, 1996-2009 (Box 9)
- Correspondence Series, 1935-2010 and undated, 79 boxes
  Arranged in two subseries: correspondence with individuals and organizations, and correspondence related to his publications. Within the first, folders are arranged alphabetically, and the documents inside the folders are in reverse chronological order. Each lettered subseries begins with General Correspondence folders in which the documents are chronologically arranged. Following the General Correspondence file are the folders named either by correspondent, or by institution, topic, group or region. The second subgrouping is arranged by correspondence with publishers of his textbooks.
  - Correspondence with individuals and organizations, 1935-2010 and undated, 70 boxes
    Includes Samuelson's professional correspondence not only with economists, but with organizations and professionals in other domains, including political figures such as Presidents John F. Kennedy, Jimmy Carter, and Bill Clinton. There are many notable economists represented in the series, including Sir John Hicks, Frank Knight, Don Patinkin, Milton Friedman, Franco Modigliani, and others. Scholars from other disciplines, among them Noam Chomsky and Alfred J. Lotka are also present. Correspondence ranges from letters in the 1930s by Sir John Hicks and Frank Knight to posthumous correspondence on special journal issues about Samuelson's life and work. Prolific correspondents represented in the collection include Peter Bernstein, John Chipman, and Don Patinkin. Along with the letters, some folders contain drafts of articles or research, usually with Samuelson's enclosed comments or feedback; one of the earliest documents is a 1935 exam given in Jacob Viner's economics course at the University of Chicago. Other folders include correspondence by several authors on specific subjects such as "Latane, Tobin and Markowitz on risk and uncertainty in portfolio management." There are also folders containing documents related to particular organizations, publication, and countries or regions such as China, India, Korea and South America.
    - General Correspondence: A, 1945-2009, 1-2 of 5 folders (Box 9)
    - General Correspondence: A, 1945-2009, 3-5 of 5 folders (Box 10)
    - Adams, Robert, 1950-2000 (Box 10)
    - Addison, Wesley, 1957-1961 (Box 10)
    - Ahmad, Syed, 1967-1991 (Box 10)
    - Air Force: Cambridge Research Center, 1951 (Box 10)
    - Aldis, Owen, 1960-1962 (Box 10)
    - Allais, Maurice, 1953-2008 (Box 10)
    - Allen, Loring, 1981-1983 (Box 10)
    - Allied Van Lines, 1982 (Box 10)
    - American Bankers Association, 1963-1967 (Box 11)
    - American Economic Review, 1941-2000, 3 folders (Box 11)
    - American Institute for Economic Research, 1961-1962 (Box 11)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1958-2008 (Box 11)
    - American Statistical Association, 1943-1950 (Box 11)
    - Amir, Shmuel, 1990-1992 (Box 11)
    - Arbitrage Mutual Fund, 1969-1972 (Box 11)
    - Archives, Duke, 1992-2006 (Box 11)
    - Arnold, Roger, 1988-1991 (Box 11)
    - Arrow, Kenneth, 1947-2008 (Box 12)
    - Arsenis, Gerry, 1963 (Box 12)
    - Ashbrook, Art, 1942-1995 (Box 12)
    - General Correspondence: B, 1939-2010, 1-5 of 16 folders (Box 12)
    - General Correspondence: B, 1939-2010, 6-11 of 16 folders (Box 13)
    - General Correspondence: B, 1939-2010, 12-16 of 16 folders (Box 14)
    - Bach, Dr. G. L. (American Economics Association), 1952-1976 (Box 14)
    - Bain, Joe, 1941-1991 (Box 14)
    - Balanced Budget Amendment, 1992 (Box 15)
    - Balassa, Bela, 1962-1991 (Box 15)
    - Balderston, Dr. C. Canby (Board of Governors), 1956-1967 (Box 15)
    - Banerjee, Kali, 1977-2000, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Baumol, William J., 1949-2008 (Box 15)
    - Becker, Gary, 1957-1993 (Box 15)
    - Beckerman, Martin, 1950-1991 (Box 15)
    - Benjamin, William A., 1960-1964 (Box 15)
    - Bennion, Dr. Edward G., 1944-1961 (Box 15)
    - Bentick, B. L., 1980 (Box 15)
    - Bergson, Abe, 1942-2005 (Box 16)
    - Bernadotte, Count Graf, 1979-1989 (Box 16)
    - Bernstein, Peter, 1948-2009, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Bhagwati, Prof. Jagdish, 1957-2008, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Bicksler, Jim, 1968-1992 (Box 17)
    - Bidard, Christian, 1983-2007 (Box 17)
    - Bilanz, Switzerland, 1990 (Box 17)
    - Birdsall, William C., 1975-1976 (Box 17)
    - Blanchard, Olivier, 1984-2009 (Box 17)
    - Blaug, Mark, 1987-2008 (Box 17)
    - Blinder, Alan, 1974-2009 (Box 17)
    - Blough, Roy (Columbia), 1947-1983 (Box 17)
    - Blume, Marshall, 1989-1990 (Box 17)
    - Board of Economic Consultants, 1968 (Box 17)
    - Bodie, Zvi, 1979-2009 (Box 17)
    - Bogle, John (Vanguard), 1990-2009 (Box 17)
    - Boston Foundation, 1984-2007 (Box 18)
    - Boston Globe, 1991 (Box 18)
    - Boulding, Kenneth, 1948-1951 (Box 18)
    - Brems, Hans, 1960-1991 (Box 18)
    - Brittain, John, 1946-1962 (Box 18)
    - Bronfenbrenner, Martin, 1943-1992, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Brookings Institute, 1954-1998 (Box 18)
    - Buchard, John, 1948-1950 (Box 18)
    - Burden, William, 1966-1985 (Box 18)
    - Bureau of the Budget, 1947-1953 (Box 18)
    - Burk, Monroe, 1960-1961 (Box 18)
    - Burmeister, Edwin, 1965-2006, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Burns, Arthur, 1946-1965 (Box 19)
    - Business Today, 1993 (Box 19)
    - General Correspondence: C, 1941-2009, 3 of 11 folders (Box 19)
    - General Correspondence: C, 1941-2009, 4-9 of 11 folders (Box 20)
    - General Correspondence: C, 1941-2009, 10-11 of 11 folders (Box 21)
    - Canadian Journal of Economics, 1967-1971 (Box 21)
    - Carter, Jimmy, 1976-1979 (Box 21)
    - Catchings, Waddill, 1952-1953 (Box 21)
    - CBS Network, Feb. 19, 1961 (Box 21)
    - Center for Economic Development, Monetary Policy Committee, 1947-1964 (Box 21)
    - Center for Real Estate Development, 1985-1990 (Box 21)
    - Chakravarty, Sukhamoy, 1961-1990 (Box 21)
    - Chang, Nelson (Reynolds and Co.), 1959-1965 (Box 21)
    - China, 1954-2008 (Box 22)
    - Chipman, John, 1950-2009, 3 folders (Box 22)
    - Chomsky, Noam, 1974-1990 (Box 22)
    - Chow, Gregory, 1956-1997 (Box 22)
    - Christian Science Monitor, 1959-1991 (Box 22)
    - Christenson, Charles, 1973-1988 (Box 22)
    - Clinton for President (includes correspondence from Clinton), 1992-1998 (Box 22)
    - Commission on Money and Credit, 1960-1962 (Box 22)
    - Cohen, Joel, 1970-1999 (Box 23)
    - Coleman, William, 1989-2004 (Box 23)
    - Columbia University Visiting Committee, 1984-1988 (Box 23)
    - Commodities Corporation, 1970-1995 (Box 23)
    - Congressional Budget Office, 1975-1994 (Box 23)
    - Congressional Joint Economic Committee, 1957-1974 (Box 23)
    - Cooper, William, 1991-1998 (Box 23)
    - Corriere della Sera, 1991-2002 (Box 23)
    - Council of Economic Advisors, 1961-1965 (Box 23)
    - Cover, Thomas, 1988-1991 (Box 24)
    - Critics and cranks, 1967-1972 (Box 24)
    - Crow, James, 1977-1993, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - General Correspondence: D, 1942-2009, 1-4 of 5 folders (Box 24)
    - General Correspondence: D, 1942-2009, 5 of 5 folders (Box 25)
    - Davidson, Basil G., 1964-2003 (Box 25)
    - Dasgupta, Partha, 1994-2008 (Box 25)
    - Day, Richard, 1975-2005 (Box 25)
    - Debreu, Gerard, 1950-1981 (Box 25)
    - Demetrius, Lloyd, 1972-1992 (Box 25)
    - Democratic Policy Council, Economic Affairs Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 25)
    - Democratic State Advisory Council, 1967 (Box 25)
    - Dennis, Ken, 1978-1979 (Box 25)
    - Dept. of State (Hawkins), 1950-1951 (Box 25)
    - Desai, Padma, 1981-2007 (Box 25)
    - Despres, Emile, 1952-1973 (Box 25)
    - Deutch, John (MIT Chemistry Dept.), 1974-2007 (Box 25)
    - Dewey, Donald, 1985-1999 (Box 25)
    - Diewert, W. E., 1973-2002 (Box 26)
    - Dillon, Douglas, 1961-1965 (Box 26)
    - Dixit, Avinash, 1975-2009 (Box 26)
    - Diamond, Hymen, 1969-1997 (Box 26)
    - Diamond, Peter, 1962-2008 (Box 26)
    - Domar, Evsey, 1945-2004 (Box 26)
    - Dorfman, Robert (Harvard), 1949-2006 (Box 26)
    - Dostaler, Gilles, 1993-1996 (Box 26)
    - Douglas, Paul H., 1947-1980 (Box 26)
    - General Correspondence: E, 1942-2008, 1-2 of 5 folders (Box 26)
    - General Correspondence: E, 1942-2008, 3-5 of 5 folders (Box 27)
    - Earley, James, 1977-1993 (Box 27)
    - Econometric Society, 1942-1994 (Box 27)
    - Economic Journal, 1951-2004 (Box 27)
    - Sub-committee on the Problems of Economic Stability, 1945-1949 (Box 28)
    - Elgar, Edward, 1992-2009 (Box 28)
    - Ellis, Howard, 1942-1949 (Box 28)
    - Elzinga, Kenneth, 1990-1992 (Box 28)
    - Erdilek, Asim, 1975-1976 (Box 28)
    - Etula, Erkko, 2004-2009 (Box 28)
    - General Correspondence: F, 1939-2009, 1 of 6 folders (Box 28)
    - General Correspondence: F, 1939-2009, 2-6 of 6 folders (Box 29)
    - Factor Price Equalization (Gale, Harrod, McKenzie, Nikaido), 1960-1972 (Box 29)
    - Fahm, L. A., 1964-1974 (Box 29)
    - Fand, David I., 1949-2002 (Box 30)
    - Federal Judges (Center for Law and Economics), 1982-1996 (Box 30)
    - Federal Reserve, 1941-2009, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Feiwel, George, 1973-2005 (Box 30)
    - Feldstein, Marty, 1972-2008 (Box 30)
    - Fellner, William, 1944-1983 (Box 30)
    - Fels, Rendigs T. (Vanderbilt), 1961-1977 (Box 30)
    - Financial Times, 1955-1966 (Box 30)
    - Fischer, Stanley, 1968-2009 (Box 31)
    - Fishburn, Peter, 1988-1996 (Box 31)
    - Fisher and Taussig Competition, 1970-1971 (Box 31)
    - Fletcher School, 1946-1949 (Box 31)
    - Fogel, Robert, 1963-2007 (Box 31)
    - Foley, Duncan, 1968-2005 (Box 31)
    - Ford Foundation, 1955-1969 (Box 31)
    - Freeman, Harold, 1944-1998 (Box 31)
    - Friedlander, Nan, 1962-1992 (Box 31)
    - Friedman, Ben, 1988-2009 (Box 31)
    - Friedman, Milton (U. of Chicago), 1949-2009 (Box 31)
    - Frisch, Ragnar, 1948-1980 (Box 32)
    - General Correspondence: G, 1940-2009, 1-2 of 8 folders (Box 32)
    - General Correspondence: G, 1940-2009, 1-6 of 8 folders (Box 32)
    - General Correspondence: G, 1940-2009, 7-8 of 8 folders (Box 33)
    - Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1946-2008 (Box 33)
    - Gale, David (U.C. Berkeley), 1959-1997 (Box 33)
    - Georgescu-Roegen, Nicholas, 1950-1998 (Box 33)
    - Gerschenkron, Alexander, 1963-2002 (Box 33)
    - Gibbs (Lecture), 1972-1975 (Box 33)
    - Gifts (from Samuelson), 1965-1984 (Box 33)
    - Gill, Richard, 1987-1990 (Box 33)
    - Glass, David, 1975-1977 (Box 33)
    - Gleason, Andrew, 1975-2001 (Box 33)
    - Gollier, Christian, 1995-2008 (Box 34)
    - Goodwin, Richard, 1946-1996 (Box 34)
    - Gordon, Wendell, 1978-1984 (Box 34)
    - Greenough, William, 1949-1990 (Box 34)
    - Grubel, H. G., 1977 and undated (Box 34)
    - Guggenheim Foundation, 1947-1993 (Box 34)
    - Gurley, John, 1964-1981 (Box 34)
    - General Correspondence: H, 1940-2009, 1-4 of 10 folders (Box 34)
    - General Correspondence: H, 1940-2009, 5-10 of 10 folders (Box 35)
    - Haavelmo, Trygve, 1947-2004 (Box 35)
    - Haberler, Gottfried, 1951-1997 (Box 36)
    - Hagen, Everett, 1943-1992 (Box 36)
    - Hahn, Frank, 1960-2007 (Box 36)
    - Hakansson, Nils, 1971-1989 (Box 36)
    - Haley, Bernard (Boulding manuscript), 1950-1952 (Box 36)
    - Hall, Lady, 1949-1995 (Box 36)
    - Hansen, Alvin H., 1939-2002 (Box 36)
    - Harcourt, Geoffrey (U. of Adelaide), 1965-1999 (Box 36)
    - Harcourt, Brace (and Co.), 1948-1951 (Box 36)
    - Harris, Seymour E. (U.C. San Diego), 1943-1973 (Box 37)
    - Harrod, R. F., 1948-1969 (Box 37)
    - Hartwick, John, 1976-2002 (Box 37)
    - Harvard Visiting Committee, 1980-1988 (Box 37)
    - Hasson, Joseph A., 1972-1974 (Box 37)
    - Hatsorpoulos, George, 1975-1992 (Box 37)
    - Hausman, Jerry, 1994-1999 (Box 37)
    - Hayek, F., 1949-1966 (Box 37)
    - Heertje, Arnold, 1960-2007 (Box 37)
    - Heilbroner, R., 1964-2005 (Box 37)
    - Heller, Walter W. (U. of Minnesota), 1947-1987 (Box 37)
    - Hicks and the Turnpike Theory (Arrow, Hitch, Kaldor, McKenzie, Morishima et al.), 1959-1960 (Box 37)
    - Hicks, Sir John, 1938-1994 (Box 37)
    - Hicks, Mrs. Ursula, 1949-1960 (Box 37)
    - Hinshaw, Randall, 1946-1997 (Box 37)
    - History of Political Economy, 1988-2008 (Box 38)
    - Hollander, Sam, 1980-2008, 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Holton, Gerald, 1963-2007 (Box 38)
    - Horton, Thomas, 1974-1998 (Box 38)
    - Houthakker, Hendrik S., 1949-2008 (Box 38)
    - Hurwicz, Leonid, 1940-2007 (Box 39)
    - General Correspondence: I, 1945-2009, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - India, 1952-2008 (Box 39)
    - Instructional Dynamics Inc. (re: Economics Cassettes series), 1968-1977 (Box 39)
    - International Economics Association, 1965-1970 (Box 39)
    - International Monetary Fund, 1948-1961 (Box 39)
    - Institute Professor, 1963-1979 (Box 39)
    - Intercollegiate Debate, 1960-1961 (Box 39)
    - Intrilligator, Michael, 1962-1984 (Box 40)
    - Irwin, Douglas, 1986-2009 (Box 40)
    - Israel, 1982-1993 (Box 40)
    - Italy, 1949-2009 (Box 40)
    - General Correspondence: J, 1940-2008, 4 folders (Box 40)
    - James, Ralph C., 1966-1970 (Box 41)
    - Japan, 1951-1999 (Box 41)
    - Japan-U.S. Center (NYU), 1985-2005 (Box 41)
    - Johnson, Dudley (U. of Washington), 1956-2004 (Box 41)
    - Johnson, Harry G., 1951-1977 (Box 41)
    - Jones, Ronald, 1956-2008 (Box 41)
    - Jorgenson, Dale, 1964-2008 (Box 41)
    - Joskow, Paul, 1975-2009 (Box 42)
    - Journal of Economic Literature, 1971-1986 (Box 42)
    - Journal of History of Economic Thought, 1999-2002 (Box 42)
    - Journal of International Economics, 1970-1990 (Box 42)
    - Journal of Political Economy, 1946-1986 (Box 42)
    - Journal of Public Economics, 1971-1985 (Box 42)
    - General Correspondence: K, 1947-2009, 1-4 of 6 folders (Box 42)
    - General Correspondence: K, 1947-2009, 5-6 of 6 folders (Box 43)
    - Kac, Mark (Truesdell), 1968-1982 (Box 43)
    - Kahn, Richard, 1948-1984 (Box 43)
    - Kaldor, Nicholas, 1946-1992 (Box 43)
    - Kemp, Professor Murray C., 1964-2001 (Box 43)
    - Kennedy, Charles, 1962-1972 (Box 43)
    - Kennedy, Edward M., 1968-1994 (Box 43)
    - Kennedy, J.F., 1958-2010, 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Kennedy: Outlook on next year's business activities in the USA and Europe (with Arthur Burns), 1962 (Box 44)
    - Kennedy Administration: On cutting taxes, 1962 (Box 44)
    - Kennedy: Oral History Project, 1964-2005 (Box 44)
    - Reports to Kennedy, 1960-1962 (Box 44)
    - Report to Kennedy and reactions, January 1961 (Box 44)
    - Kennedy, J.F. Presidential Papers (recordings transcripts on tax cut proposals), 1962-1963 (Box 44)
    - Kennedy, Robert, 1968 (Box 44)
    - Keyfitz, Nathan, 1958-2009 (Box 44)
    - Keyserling, Leon, 1948-1985 (Box 45)
    - Khan, Ali, 1989-2008 (Box 45)
    - Khoury, Philip S., 1996-2006 (Box 45)
    - Killan, James R. (President), 1944-1954 (Box 45)
    - Kindleberger, Charles P., M.I.T., 1948-2003 (Box 45)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1956-1975 (Box 45)
    - Klein, Lawrence, 1944-2006 (Box 45)
    - Knight, Frank, 1937-1958 (Box 45)
    - Kohn, Robert, 1987-1996 (Box 45)
    - Koopmans, Tjalling, 1946-1985 (Box 45)
    - Korea, 1957-2008 (Box 45)
    - Kovner, Bruce, 1991-2002 (Box 45)
    - Kremen, Bennett, 1972-1973 (Box 45)
    - Kritzman, Mark, 1991-2007 (Box 45)
    - Kruskal, William H., 1975-1980 (Box 45)
    - Krugman, Paul, 1986-2009 (Box 46)
    - Kuh, Edwin, 1957-1986 (Box 46)
    - Kurz, Heinz, 1984-2010, 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Kuznets, Simon, 1944-1986 (Box 46)
    - General Correspondence: L, 1939-2010, 1 of 6 folders (Box 46)
    - General Correspondence: L, 1939-2010, 5-6 of 6 folders (Box 47)
    - Labini, Paolo S. (festschrift), 1988-1990 (Box 47)
    - Laffer, Arthur, 1971 (Box 47)
    - Laibman, David, 1973-1974 (Box 47)
    - Laidler, David, 1982-2003 (Box 48)
    - Lange, Oskar, 1938-1946 (Box 48)
    - Latane, Tobin, Markowitz (risk and uncertainty in portfolio management), 1956-1969 (Box 48)
    - Leontief, Wassily, 1945-1999 (Box 48)
    - Lerner, Abba, 1942-1990 (Box 48)
    - Levy, Haim, 1990-1998, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Lindbeck, Assar, 1984-2009 (Box 48)
    - Little, Ian, 1948-2005 (Box 48)
    - Lo, Andrew, 1988-1994 (Box 48)
    - Loomis-Sayles, 1961-1965 (Box 48)
    - Lotka, 1942 (Box 48)
    - Low, Francis, 1980-2007 (Box 48)
    - Luce, Duncan/Savage, Jimmie (utility and portfolios), 1968 (Box 49)
    - Lundberg, Erik (The Stockholm School of Economics), 1968-1989 (Box 49)
    - General Correspondence: M, 1944-2009, 1-6 of 13 folders (Box 49)
    - General Correspondence: M, 1944-2009, 7-11 of 13 folders (Box 50)
    - General Correspondence: M, 1944-2009, 12-13 of 13 folders (Box 51)
    - Machina, Mark, 1985-2009 (Box 51)
    - Machlup, Fritz (Princeton University), 1941-1978 (Box 51)
    - MacKenzie, Donald, 1999-2006 (Box 51)
    - Mackey, George W., 1969-2006 (Box 51)
    - MacNeil/Lehrer Newshour, 1992 (Box 51)
    - Madden, Paul, 1983-1989 (Box 51)
    - Mandelbrot, Benoit, 1961-1998 (Box 51)
    - Mankin, Wyatt, 1978-1990 (Box 52)
    - Marglin, Professor Stephen A. (Harvard University), 1971-1988 (Box 52)
    - Markowitz, Harry, 1985-2009 (Box 52)
    - Marsh, Stanley 3rd (Amarillo, Texas), 1968-2003 (Box 52)
    - Martinas, Katalin, 1992-1993 (Box 52)
    - Mas-Colell, Andrew, 1987-2007 (Box 52)
    - Edward Mason Fund, 1984-1992 (Box 52)
    - McCallum, Bennett, 1996-1997 (Box 52)
    - McCracken, Paul W. (U. of Michigan, Council of Economic Advisers), 1946-2005 (Box 52)
    - McGovern, George, 1972 (Box 52)
    - McKenzie, Lionel, 1947-2002 (Box 52)
    - McManus, Maurice, 1957-1974 (Box 52)
    - Meade, James E., 1949-1996 (Box 52)
    - Meet the Press, 1961-1971 (Box 52)
    - Merton, Robert C., 1969-2009 (Box 52)
    - Merton, Robert K., 1959-2003 (Box 53)
    - Metzler, Lloyd A. (U. of Chicago), 1944-1991 (Box 53)
    - Mexico, 1955-1997 (Box 53)
    - Miller, Edward, 1978-1985 (Box 53)
    - Miller, Taulman (Indiana University), 1960-1962 (Box 53)
    - Millikan, Max and Jane, 1946-1993 (Box 53)
    - Mirowski, Philip, 1985-1997 (Box 53)
    - Mirrlees, James, 1963-1993 (Box 53)
    - MIT, 1940-2007 (Box 53)
    - Miyazaki, Koichi, 1989-1991 (Box 53)
    - Modigliani, Franco, 1943-2008 (Box 53)
    - Mondale, Walter, 1974 (Box 53)